<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<database title="Open Halon Configuration Database">
  <p>
    A database with this schema holds the configuration for one Open
    Halon system.
  </p>
  <p>
    The schema is derived from Open vSwitch schema.
    Tables/attributes which are not related to Open Halon first open source release
    (OSR1) were removed. Additionally the schema was extended to include OSR1
    features that don't exist in Open vSwitch, as well as information
    specific to a physical switch.
    Going forward, the expectation is to restore the Open vSwitch parts
    of the schema that were removed as we implement additional features.
  </p>
  <p>
    The top-level configuration is the
    <ref table="System"/> table, which must have exactly one
    record. Records that are not reachable from
    the <ref table="System"/> table are automatically deleted
    from the database, except for records in a few distinguished
    ``root set'' tables.
  </p>
  <p>
    Note that a basic tenet of the Open Halon schema is that in the absence of any
    configuration, the default behavior of the Open Halon switch is such that
    no data traffic can be accepted or transmitted on any port or interface.
    Any future additions to the Open Halon schema must adhere to this principle.
  </p>

  <h2>Common Columns</h2>

  <p>
    Many tables contain two special columns, named <code>other_config</code>
    and <code>external_ids</code>. These columns have the same form and
    purpose each place that they appear, so we describe them here to save space
    later.
  </p>

  <dl>
    <dt><code>other_config</code>: map of string-string pairs</dt>
    <dd>
      <p>
        Key-value pairs for configuring rarely used features.  Supported keys,
        along with the forms taken by their values, are documented individually
        for each table.
      </p>
      <p>
        A few tables do not have <code>other_config</code> columns because no
        key-value pairs have yet been defined for them.
      </p>
    </dd>

    <dt><code>external_ids</code>: map of string-string pairs</dt>
    <dd>
      Key-value pairs for use by external frameworks that integrate with Open
      Halon, rather than by Open Halon itself.  System integrators should
      either use the Open Halon development mailing list to coordinate on
      common key-value definitions, or choose key names that are likely to be
      unique.  In some cases, where key-value pairs have been defined that are
      likely to be widely useful, they are documented individually for each
      table.
    </dd>
  </dl>

  <table name="System" title="Open Halon top level configuration.">
    Configuration for an Open Halon system. There must be exactly
    one record in the <ref table="System"/> table.

    <group title="Configuration">
      <column name="subsystems">
      </column>

      <column name="bridges">
        Set of bridges.
      </column>

      <column name="vrfs">
      </column>

      <column name="management_mac">
        Ethernet MAC address for the management interface port for this system.
      </column>

      <column name="system_mac">
        Ethernet MAC address available to use anywhere a non-unique MAC is
        needed.
      </column>

      <column name="daemons">
      </column>

      <column name="ssl">
      </column>

      <column name="hostname">
      </column>

      <column name="dns_servers">
      </column>

      <column name="asset_tag_number">
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="stats-update-interval"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 5000}'>
        <p>
          Interval for updating statistics to the database, in milliseconds.
          This option will affect the update of the <code>statistics</code>
          column in the following tables: <code>Port</code>, <code>Interface
          </code>.
        </p>
        <p>
          Default value is 5000 ms.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="min_internal_vlan"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1, "maxInteger": 4094}'>
        <p>
            This key specifies a lower bound of the VLAN range, which is being used for internal system purposes.
        </p>
        <p>
            Default value is 1024.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="max_internal_vlan"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1, "maxInteger": 4094}'>
        <p>
            This key specifies an upper bound of the VLAN range, which is being used for internal system purposes.
        </p>
        <p>
            Default value is 4094.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="internal_vlan_policy"
              type='{"type": "string"}'>
        <p>
            This key indicates order of assignment of internal VLAN ID (ascending or descending).
        </p>

        <p>
            Default option is ascending order.
        </p>
      </column>

      <group title="TFTP Server Configurations">
        <column name="other_config" key="tftp_server_enable"
                type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
          Set this value to <code>true</code> to enable TFTP server
          and set to <code>false</code> to disable it. If not set, TFTP server
          would be enabled.
        </column>

        <column name="other_config" key="tftp_server_secure"
                type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
          Set this value to <code>true</code> to enable TFTP secure mode
          and set to <code>false</code> to disable it. If not set, TFTP secure mode
          would be enabled. This config is valid only if TFTP server is enabled.
        </column>
      </group>


    <group title="LACP Configurations">
      <column name="lacp_config" key="lacp-system-id">
        The LACP system ID of this <ref table="Bridge"/>.  The system ID of a
        LACP bond is used to identify itself to its partners.  Must be a
        nonzero MAC address. Defaults to the bridge Ethernet address if
        unset.
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_config" key="lacp-system-priority"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 0, "maxInteger": 65535}'>
        The LACP system priority of this <ref table="Bridge"/>.  In LACP
        negotiations, link status decisions are made by the system with the
        numerically lower priority. Defaults to 65534.
      </column>
   </group>

    <group title="LLDP Configurations">
      <column name="other_config" key="lldp_enable"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Set this value to <code>true</code> to enable System level LLDP
        or to <code>false</code> to explicitly disable it.
        Default is <code>disable</code>.
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="lldp_tlv_mgmt_addr_enable"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Set this value to <code>true</code> to enable transmission of LLDP
        Management Address TLV or set it to <code>false</code> to disable
        transmitting it.
        Default is <code>enable</code>.
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="lldp_tlv_port_desc_enable"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Set this value to <code>true</code> to enable transmission of LLDP
        Port Description TLV or set it to <code>false</code> to disable
        transmitting it.
        Default is <code>enable</code>.
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="lldp_tlv_port_vlan_enable"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Set this value to <code>true</code> to enable transmission of LLDP
        Port VLAN TLV or set it to <code>false</code> to disable
        transmitting it.
        Default is <code>enable</code>.
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="lldp_tlv_sys_cap_enable"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Set this value to <code>true</code> to enable transmission of LLDP
        System Capabilities TLV or set it to <code>false</code> to disable
        transmitting it.
        Default is <code>enable</code>.
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="lldp_tlv_sys_desc_enable"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Set this value to <code>true</code> to enable transmission of LLDP
        System Description TLV or set it to <code>false</code> to disable
        transmitting it.
        Default is <code>enable</code>.
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="lldp_tlv_sys_name_enable"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Set this value to <code>true</code> to enable transmission of LLDP
        System Name TLV or set it to <code>false</code> to disable
        transmitting it.
        Default is <code>enable</code>.
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="lldp_mgmt_addr"
              type='{"type": "string"}'>
        LLDP Management IP Address to be sent in TLV.
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="lldp_tx_interval"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 5, "maxInteger": 32768}'>
        <p>
            The interval in seconds at which LLDP status updates are
            transmitted to neighbors in seconds.
        </p>
        <p>
          Default value is 30 sec.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="lldp_hold"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 2, "maxInteger": 10}'>
        <p>
          The amount of time a receiving device should hold the information
          sent by your device before discarding it.
          This variable is used as a multiplier of lldp_tx_interval,
          to determine the value of TTL that is carried in LLDP frames.
        </p>
        <p>
          Default value is 4.
        </p>
      </column>
   </group>

   </group>

    <group title="Status">
      <column name="status">
        System level status information per service like <code>LLDP</code>, etc.
      </column>

    <group title="LLDP Status Info">
      <column name="status" key="lldp_local_mgmt_ip">
      Management IP Address currently being advertised by LLDP.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="lldp_local_system_cap">
      System Capabilities currently being advertised by LLDP.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="lldp_local_system_desc">
      System Description info currently being advertised by LLDP.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="lldp_local_system_name">
      System Name currently being advertised by LLDP.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="lldp_last_table_change_time">
      Last time when LLDP neighbor table was changed.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="lldp_num_clear_counters_requested">
      Number of times clear statistic counters was requested by user.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="lldp_last_clear_counters_performed">
      Last time when clear statistic counters was perfomed.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="lldp_num_clear_table_requested">
      Number of times clearing of neighbor table was requested by user.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="lldp_last_clear_table_performed">
      Last time when neighbor table was cleared.
      </column>
   </group>

      <column name="mgmt_intf_status">
        This column holds the status of the management interface IP parameters.
        This column contains key-value pairs that report the mangement interface
        IP attributes like IP address, subnet, default gateway, primary and
        secondary name server. These values are either statically configured by
        the user or populated by the DHCP client.
        The keys of this column is same as that of mgmt_intf column.
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf_status" key="hostname">
        Hostname the system is configured with. Hostname can be configured
        through CLI, or specified in DHCP messages. If none of these are
        available, it defaults to "switch".
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf_status" key="dhcp_hostname">
        Holds hostname configured by dhcp client.
      </column>
      <column name="next_cfg">
        Sequence number for client to increment.  When a client modifies
        any part of the database configuration and wishes to wait for
        Open Halon to finish applying the changes, it may increment
        this sequence number.
      </column>

      <column name="cur_cfg">
        Sequence number that Open Halon sets to the current value of
        <ref column="next_cfg"/> after it finishes applying a set of
        configuration changes.
      </column>

      <column name="next_hw">
        Sequence number to indicate that a change has occurred in the hardware
        configuration (e.g., a subsystem has been added or removed).
        </column>

      <column name="cur_hw">
        Sequence number that indicates the current change level for the h/w
        configuration. When <ref column="cur_hw"/> is the same as <ref
        column="next_hw"/>, then all platform daemon processing has completed
        in response to the hardware addition or removal. This is not used for
        transceiver pluggable module insertion/removal.
      </column>

      <column name="boot_time">
        Boot time of the machine, represented in seconds since 1970-01-01 00:00:00 UTC.
        OVSDB integers are 64 bit, which means it will take some time until we roll over.
      </column>
    </group>

      <group title="Statistics">
        <p>
          The <code>statistics</code> column contains key-value pairs that
          report statistics about a system running Open Halon.  These are
          updated periodically (by default, every 5 seconds).  Key-value pairs
          that cannot be determined or that do not apply to a platform are
          omitted.
        </p>

        <column name="other_config" key="enable-statistics"
                type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
          Statistics are disabled by default to avoid overhead in the common
          case when statistics gathering is not useful.  Set this value to
          <code>true</code> to enable populating the <ref column="statistics"/>
          column or to <code>false</code> to explicitly disable it.
        </column>

        <column name="statistics" key="cpu"
                type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1}'>
          <p>
            Number of CPU processors, threads, or cores currently online and
            available to the operating system,
            as an integer.  This may be less than the number installed, if some
            are not online or if they are not available to the operating
            system.
          </p>
        </column>

        <column name="statistics" key="load_average">
          A comma-separated list of three floating-point numbers,
          representing the system load average over the last 1, 5, and 15
          minutes, respectively.
        </column>

        <column name="statistics" key="memory">
          <p>
            A comma-separated list of integers, each of which represents a
            quantity of memory in kilobytes that describes the operating
            system.  In respective order,
            these values are:
          </p>

          <ol>
            <li>Total amount of RAM allocated to the OS.</li>
            <li>RAM allocated to the OS that is in use.</li>
            <li>RAM that can be flushed out to disk or otherwise discarded
            if that space is needed for another purpose.  This number is
            necessarily less than or equal to the previous value.</li>
            <li>Total disk space allocated for swap.</li>
            <li>Swap space currently in use.</li>
          </ol>
        </column>

        <column name="statistics" key="process_NAME">
          <p>
            One such key-value pair, with <code>NAME</code> replaced by
            a process name, will exist for each running Open Halon
            daemon process, with <var>name</var> replaced by the
            daemon's name (e.g. <code>process_sysd</code>).  The
            value is a comma-separated list of integers.  The integers
            represent the following, with memory measured in kilobytes
            and durations in milliseconds:
          </p>

          <ol>
            <li>The process's virtual memory size.</li>
            <li>The process's resident set size.</li>
            <li>The amount of user and system CPU time consumed by the
            process.</li>
            <li>The number of times that the process has crashed and been
            automatically restarted by the monitor.</li>
            <li>The duration since the process was started.</li>
            <li>The duration for which the process has been running.</li>
          </ol>

          <p>
            The interpretation of some of these values depends on whether the
            process was started with the <option>--monitor</option>.  If it
            was not, then the crash count will always be 0 and the two
            durations will always be the same.  If <option>--monitor</option>
            was given, then the crash count may be positive; if it is, the
            latter duration is the amount of time since the most recent crash
            and restart.
          </p>

          <p>
            There will be one key-value pair for each file in Open Halon's
            ``run directory'' (usually <code>/var/run/openvswitch</code>)
            whose name ends in <code>.pid</code>, whose contents are a
            process ID, and which is locked by a running process.  The
            <var>name</var> is taken from the pidfile's name.
          </p>
        </column>

        <column name="statistics" key="file_systems">
          <p>
            A space-separated list of information on local, writable file
            systems.  Each item in the list describes one file system and
            consists in turn of a comma-separated list of the following:
          </p>

          <ol>
            <li>Mount point, e.g. <code>/</code> or <code>/var/log</code>.
            Any spaces or commas in the mount point are replaced by
            underscores.</li>
            <li>Total size, in kilobytes, as an integer.</li>
            <li>Amount of storage in use, in kilobytes, as an integer.</li>
          </ol>

          <p>
            This key-value pair is omitted if there are no local, writable
            file systems or if Open Halon cannot obtain the needed
            information.
          </p>
        </column>

    <group title="LLDP Statistics">
        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_table_inserts">
            Number of neighbor entries inserted to LLDP neighbor table.
            Default is 0.
        </column>

        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_table_deletes">
            Number of neighbor entries deleted from LLDP neighbor table.
            Default is 0.
        </column>

        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_table_drops">
            Number of neighbor entries that could not be added to LLDP
            neighbor table and dropped.
            Default is 0.
        </column>

        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_table_ageouts">
            Number of times neighbor info was deleted from LLDP neighbor
            table because of the TTL timer associated with a neighbor
            has expired.
            Default is 0.
        </column>
    </group>

    </group>

    <group title="Version Reporting">
      <p>
        These columns report the types and versions of the hardware and
        software running Open Halon.  We recommend in general that software
        should test whether specific features are supported instead of relying
        on version number checks.  These values are primarily intended for
        reporting to human administrators.
      </p>

      <column name="switch_version">
        The Open Halon version number, e.g. <code>0.1.0</code>.
      </column>

      <column name="db_version">
        <p>
          The database schema version number in the form
          <code><var>major</var>.<var>minor</var>.<var>tweak</var></code>,
          e.g. <code>1.2.3</code>.  Whenever the database schema is changed in
          a non-backward compatible way (e.g. deleting a column or a table),
          <var>major</var> is incremented.  When the database schema is changed
          in a backward compatible way (e.g. adding a new column),
          <var>minor</var> is incremented.  When the database schema is changed
          cosmetically (e.g. reindenting its syntax), <var>tweak</var> is
          incremented.
        </p>

        <p>
          The schema version is part of the database schema, so it can also be
          retrieved by fetching the schema using the Open vSwitch database
          protocol.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="software_info" key="bios_release_date">
      </column>

      <column name="software_info" key="bios_vendor">
      </column>

      <column name="software_info" key="bios_version">
      </column>

      <column name="software_info" key="boot_loader">
      </column>

      <column name="software_info" key="boot_loader_version">
      </column>

      <column name="software_info" key="diag_version">
      </column>

      <column name="software_info" key="install_env">
      </column>

      <column name="software_info" key="install_env_version">
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Database Configuration">
      <p>
        These columns primarily configure the Open Halon database
        (<code>ovsdb-server</code>), not the Open Halon switch
        (<code>pswitchd</code>).  The OVSDB database also uses the <ref
        column="ssl"/> settings.
      </p>

      <p>
        The Open Halon switch does read the database configuration to
        determine remote IP addresses to which in-band control should apply.
      </p>
      <column name="aaa" key="radius" type='{"type": "string"}'>
        This column used for AAA feature. The valid values for the key 'radius'
        are true or false based on the user request for authentication.
        If radius=true, radius based authentication is enabled. By default
        authentication is local.
      </column>
      <column name="aaa" key="fallback" type='{"type": "string"}'>
        This column used for AAA feature. The valid values for the key 'fallback'
        are true or false based on the user request for authentication. If
        fallback=true, fall to local authentication if radius server is not reachable.
      </column>
      <column name="manager_options">
        Database clients to which the Open Halon database server should
        connect or to which it should listen, along with options for how these
        connection should be configured.  See the <ref table="Manager"/> table
        for more information.
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf">
        This column is a map of string-string pairs
        Management interface column contains the attributes of management
        interface. The keys are name, mode, ip, subnet mask, default gateway,
        dns server IPv4 addresses. This column holds values that are configured
        by the user.
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf" key="name" >
        The value for this key is a valid interface name that is to be
        configured as management interface
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf" key="mode" >
        The value is static or dhcp based on the mode in which the management
        ip is to be obtained. Default value is dhcp.
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf" key="ip" >
        The value for this key is interface IPv4 address of the management interface.
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf" key="subnet_mask" >
        The value for this key is subnet mask of the interface IP of management
        interface in CIDR format. The valid value range is 1 to 31.
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf" key="default_gateway" >
        The value for this key is default gateway IPv4 address.
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf" key="dns_server_1" >
        The value for this key is Primary nameserver IPv4 address.
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf" key="dns_server_2" >
        The value for this key is Secondary nameserver IPv4 address.
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf" key="ipv6" >
        The value for this key is IPv6 address of the management interface.
        Possible value X:X::X:X/M.
      </column>
      <column name="mgmt_intf" key="default_gateway_v6" >
        The value for this key is default gateway IPv6 address
      </column>
      <column name="radius_servers">
        Specifies radius servers configuration. See the <ref table="Radius_Server"/>
        table for more information.
      </column>
      <column name="auto_provisioning_status" key="performed" type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Specifies whether auto-provisioning was performed. False if not specified.
      </column>
      <column name="auto_provisioning_status" key="url">
        Specifies the URL that was used to fetch auto-provisioning script. Would not be
        present if auto-provisioning was not performed.
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Logrotate configuration">
        <column name="logrotate_config" key="period" type='{"type": "string"}'>
            The user configured period of logrotation. The possible values are
            'hourly','daily','weekly'or 'monthly'.
            Default value is 'daily'
        </column>

        <column name="logrotate_config" key="maxsize"
                type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1, "maxInteger": 200}'>
            Log size (in megabytes), which would trigger rotation. 10 megabytes if not specified
        </column>

        <column name="logrotate_config" key="target" type='{"type": "string"}'>
            The user configured URI of the remote host .The valid value is
            'tftp://A.B.C.D'.If not specified log files will be rotated locally.
        </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Bufmon configuration">
      <column name="bufmon_config" key="enabled"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Specifies whether the bufmon feature is enabled on the system.
        False, if the value is not present.
      </column>

      <column name="bufmon_config" key="counters_mode"
                type='{"type": "string", "enum": ["set", ["peak", "current"]]}'>
        Specifies whether counters should report their current values or peak values
        since last collection.
      </column>

      <column name="bufmon_config" key="periodic_collection_enabled"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Specifies whether periodic collection of the counters is enabled.
        False, if the value is not present.
      </column>

      <column name="bufmon_config" key="collection_period"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1}'>
        Specifies the period of collection in seconds.
        Five, if the value is not present.
      </column>

      <column name="bufmon_config" key="threshold_trigger_collection_enabled"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Specifies whether counters should be collected immediately
        when one of the thresholds is crossed.
        True, if the value is not present.
      </column>

      <column name="bufmon_config" key="threshold_trigger_rate_limit"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1, "maxInteger": 600}'>
        Specifies maximum number of trigger generated reports per minute.
        The limit will be averaged and imposed on a per second basis.
        For example, value of 600 will allow report every 100ms.
        If no value is set, the default is 60 i.e. once per second.
      </column>

      <column name="bufmon_config" key="snapshot_on_threshold_trigger"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Specifies whether counters should be frozen when one of the thresholds is crossed.
        True, if the value is not present.
      </column>

    </group>
    <group title="Information">
      <column name="bufmon_info" key="cap_mode_peak"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Specifies whether the system is capable of collecting peak values of
        the counters.
        False, if the value is not present.
      </column>
      <column name="bufmon_info" key="cap_mode_current"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Specifies whether the system is capable of collecting current values of
        the counters.
        False, if the value is not present.
      </column>
      <column name="bufmon_info" key="cap_snapshot_on_threshold_trigger"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Specifies whether the system is capable of freezing counters values on
        threshold crossing.
        False, if the value is not present.
      </column>
      <column name="bufmon_info" key="cap_threshold_trigger_collection"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        Specifies whether the system is capable of immediately collecting values on
        threshold crossing.
        False, if the value is not present.
      </column>
      <column name="bufmon_info" key="last_collection_timestamp"
              type='{"type": "integer"}'>
        Specifies the timestamp of the last collection in seconds from Jan 1, 1970.
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="ECMP configuration">
      <p>
        Specifies the various ECMP (Equal Cost Multi-Path) configuration options.
      </p>

        <column name="ecmp_config" key="enabled" type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
            Determines whether ECMP is enabled in the system.
            Default is true.
        </column>
        <column name="ecmp_config" key="hash_srcip_enabled" type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
            Determines whether source IP participates in ECMP hash calculation.
            Default is true.
        </column>
        <column name="ecmp_config" key="hash_dstip_enabled" type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
            Determines whether destination IP participates in ECMP hash
            calculation.
            Default is true.
        </column>
        <column name="ecmp_config" key="hash_srcport_enabled" type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
            Determines whether source TCP/UDP port participates in ECMP hash
            calculation.
            Default is true.
        </column>
        <column name="ecmp_config" key="hash_dstport_enabled" type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
            Determines whether destination TCP/UDP port participates in ECMP
            hash calculation.
            Default is true.
        </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config"/>
      <column name="external_ids"/>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Subsystem" title="system board, daughter card, line card, etc.">
    <group title="Configuration">
      <column name="interfaces">
      </column>
      <column name="leds">
      </column>
      <column name="fans">
      </column>
      <column name="temp_sensors">
      </column>
      <column name="power_supplies">
      </column>
      <column name="asset_tag_number">
      </column>
    </group>
    <group title="Hardware Configuration">
      <column name="next_mac_address">
        Next available (unused) Ethernet MAC address from the MAC address pool
        for this subsystem.
      </column>
      <column name="macs_remaining">
        The number of available (unused) Ethernet MAC address from the MAC
        address pool for this subsystem.
      </column>
    </group>
    <group title="Inventory Info">
      <column name="name">
      </column>
      <column name="hw_desc_dir">
        Directory where the hardware description files for this subsystem
        are located.
      </column>
      <column name="type">
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="device_version" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="diag_version" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="label_revision" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="base_mac_address" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="number_of_macs" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="onie_version" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="manufacturer" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="vendor" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="part_number" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="platform_name" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="serial_number" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="manufacture_date" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="country_code" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="height" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="interface_count" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="max_interface_speed" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="max_transmission_unit" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="max_bond_count" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="max_bond_member_count" >
      </column>
      <column name="other_info" key="l3_port_requires_internal_vlan" >
      </column>
    </group>
    <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config" key="fan_speed_override"
          type='{"type": "string", "enum": ["set", ["slow", "normal", "medium", "fast", "max"]]}'>
        If the fan_speed_override value is set, <code>fand</code> uses that value
        (unless the output of <code>tempd</code> requests max speed, in which case
        the fans are set to max to avoid an over-temperature situation).
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Bridge">
    <p>
      Configuration for a bridge within an <ref table="System"/>.
    </p>
    <p>
      A <ref table="Bridge"/> record represents an Ethernet switch with one or
      more ``ports,'' which are the <ref table="Port"/> records pointed to by
      the <ref table="Bridge"/>'s <ref column="ports"/> column. In the first
      release, only one default bridge (bridge_normal) is supported
    </p>

    <group title="Core Features">
      <column name="name">
        Bridge identifier.  Should be alphanumeric and no more than about 8
        bytes long.  Must be unique among the names of ports, interfaces, and
        bridges on a host.
      </column>

      <column name="ports">
        Ports included in the bridge.
      </column>

      <column name="vlans">
        VLANs included in the bridge.
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Other Features">
      <column name="datapath_type">
        Name of datapath provider.
      </column>
      <column name="datapath_version">
      </column>
      <column name="datapath_id">
      </column>
      <column name="other_config" key="hwaddr">
        An Ethernet address in the form
        <var>xx</var>:<var>xx</var>:<var>xx</var>:<var>xx</var>:<var>xx</var>:<var>xx</var>
        to set the hardware address of the local port and influence the
        datapath ID.
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="mac-aging-time"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1}'>
        <p>
          The maximum number of seconds to retain a MAC learning entry for
          which no packets have been seen.  The default is currently 300
          seconds (5 minutes).  The value, if specified, is forced into a
          reasonable range, currently 15 to 3600 seconds.
        </p>

        <p>
          A short MAC aging time allows a network to more quickly detect that a
          host is no longer connected to a switch port.  However, it also makes
          it more likely that packets will be flooded unnecessarily, when they
          are addressed to a connected host that rarely transmits packets.  To
          reduce the incidence of unnecessary flooding, use a MAC aging time
          longer than the maximum interval at which a host will ordinarily
          transmit packets.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="mac-table-size"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1}'>
        <p>
          The maximum number of MAC addresses to learn.  The default is
          currently 16K.  The value, if specified, is forced into a reasonable
          range, currently 10 to 256K.
        </p>
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Bridge Status">
      <p>
        Status information about bridges.
      </p>
      <column name="status">
        Key-value pairs that report bridge status.
      </column>
      <column name="status" key="actual-mac-table-size">
        Actual size of the mac table.
        If mac-table-size exceeds hardware capability, then
        this field will show the real size used.
      </column>
     </group>

    <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config"/>
      <column name="external_ids"/>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="VRF" title="Virtual Routing and Forwarding">
    <p>
        Each entry in this table represents a single routing domain,
        commonly known as Virtual Routing and Forwarding.
    </p>
    <group title="Configuration">
      <column name="name">
        VRF identifier. Should be alphanumeric. VRF names must be
        unique.
      </column>

      <column name="ports">
        Ports included in the VRF.
      </column>
      <column name="bgp_routers" keyname="asn">
        BGP routers keyed by ASN value.
      </column>
      <column name="dhcp_server">
        DHCP Server in the VRF.
      </column>
    </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Daemon" title="Daemon Information">
    Each entry in this table represents a single system daemon and contains
    information about that specific daemon. One use is to identify those
    daemons that read and process hardware description files to add new
    hardware into the db.
    <group title="Configuration">
      <column name="name">
        The name of the daemon.
      </column>
      <column name="is_hw_handler">
        A boolean to indicate if this daemon is responsible for processing
        hardware description information (either on boot, or as hardware
        subsystems are added or removed).
      </column>
    </group>
    <group title="Status">
      <column name="cur_hw">
        Sequence number that a daemon sets to the current value of
        <ref column="next_hw"/> in the <ref table="System"/> table after
        it has successfully responded to a hardware change.
      </column>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Route_Map" title="Route Map">
    <group title="Global Route Map Configuration">
      <column name="name">
        Reference to the VRF table, to which this route belongs.
      </column>
      <column name="route_map_entries" keyname="preference">
        Route map entries keyed by preference value.
      </column>
    </group>
   <group title="Status">
      <column name="status" >
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>
  <table name="Route_Map_Entry" title="Route Map Entry">
    <group title="Global Route Map Entries Configuration">
      <column name="description">
      </column>
      <column name="action">
        There are three types, permit, deny, and any.
      </column>
      <column name="exitpolicy">
        Rather than normal exiting, route map can continue on processing next route map,
        or goto N route map and continue on processing.
      </column>
      <column name="goto_target">
        If exitpolicy is goto, nextpref is the route map to jump to.
      </column>
      <column name="call">
        If call command is used, nextrm indicate which route map to goto.
      </column>
      <column name="match">
        The match rule for route map. Default is deny.
      </column>
      <column name="set">
        The set rule for route map
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Status">
      <column name="status" >
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.
      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Prefix_List" title="Prefix List">
    <group title="Global IP Address Prefix List Configuration">
      <column name="name">
        Name of the prefix list.
      </column>
      <column name="prefix_list_entries" keyname="preference">
        Prefix list entries keyed by preference value.
      </column>
      <column name="description">
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Prefix_List_Entry" title="Prefix List Entry">
    <group title="Global Prefix List Entries Configuration">
      <column name="le">
      </column>
      <column name="ge">
      </column>
      <column name="action">
        There are three types, permit, deny, and any.
      </column>
      <column name="prefix">
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.
      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Route" title="Routes Information Base">
    <p>
      Global routes information base within an <ref table="System"/>.
    </p>
    <p>
        A <ref table="Route"/> record represents a route. This is a unique
        record per (vrf, prefix, protocol) set.
    </p>
    <group title="Global Routes Configuration">
      <column name="vrf">
        Reference to the VRF table, to which this route belongs.
      </column>
      <column name="prefix">
          IPv4 or IPv6 destination prefix and mask in the address/mask
          format. Example 192.168.0.0/16
      </column>
      <column name="from">
          Protocol that is responsible for this entry. The value is
          <code>BGP</code> if BGP created this entry, <code>static</code>
          when the user configures a static route and <code>connected</code>
          if it is a directly connected device.
      </column>
      <column name="protocol_private">
          Indicates that this row is a protocol specific route entry.
          The entries which have this value set, should not participate in
          routing. Example: BGP can store routes for reference and future
          selection but should not currently be used for forwarding.
          Default is <code>false</code>.
      </column>
      <column name="selected">
          Route table can have entries which may not be selected for
          forwarding. This flag indicates if this entry is selected
          as an active route for forwarding.
          Default is <code>false</code>.
      </column>
      <column name="address_family">
        Represents the address family for this entry.
        Default value is <code>ipv4</code>.
      </column>
      <column name="sub_address_family">
        Represents more information regarding this entry.
        Default is <code>unicast</code>.
      </column>
      <column name="distance">
          Administrative distance for the route entry. This value is populated
          every time a protocol or a user adds a new entry.
          The default value is 1 which is the default distance for static
          routes.
      </column>
      <column name="metric">
          This is the BGP Multi Exit Discriminator (MED) attribute used in best
          path selection. The MED provides a dynamic way to influence another AS
          in the way to reach a certain route when there are multiple entry points
          for that AS.  BGP decision process takes weight, local preference, AS path,
          Origin and MED into account.  For selection, if all other factors are equal,
          the exit point with the lowest MED is preferred.
          Default value is 0
      </column>
      <column name="nexthops">
          List of all the nexthops for this entry. This will be empty in case
          of blackhole.
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Protocol Specific">
      <p>
          The <code>protocol_specific</code> column contains key-value pairs that
          are used by the owner of the entry. Example: If BGP created an entry
          BGP can populate these key-value pairs for its internal use. These
          values may not add value to other daemons
      </p>
      <column name="protocol_specific" key="bgp_flags"
          type='{"type": "string"}'>
          Route status flags. Allowed values are <code>history</code>,
          <code>damped</code>,<code>multipath</code>
      </column>
      <column name="protocol_specific" key="bgp_as_path"
          type='{"type": "string"}'>
          List of AS path number for a route. Example: 200,300,400
      </column>
      <column name="protocol_specific" key="bgp_origin"
          type='{"type": "string"}'>
          Indicates whether a route is <code>IGP</code>, <code>EGP</code>
          or <code>incomplete</code>.
      </column>
      <column name="protocol_specific" key="bgp_loc_pref"
          type='{"type": "string"}'>
          Local preference path attribute. Used by BGP to influence in the
          best path selectionUsed by BGP to influence in the
          best path selection..
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Nexthop" title="Nexthops">
    <p>
      Global list of all the nexthops as used by the <ref table="Route"/> table.
      Each entry in the <ref table="Route"/> can have a reference to one or
      many(for ECMP) entries in this table.
    </p>
    <group title="Configuration">
      <column name="ip_address">
          IP address of the nexthop device.
      </column>
      <column name="ports">
          List of outgoing ports. Nexthop entries of type <code>unicast</code>
          can have atmost 1 port.
      </column>
      <column name="type">
          Type of the nexthop.
          Default is <code>unicast</code>.
      </column>
      <column name="selected">
          Indicates if this nexthop is actively participating in forwarding.
          Multiple nexthops can exist for each route entry but the routing protocol
          can indicate if a particular nexthop should not be used in forwarding.
          Default is <code>true</code>.
      </column>
      <column name="weight">
          Weight is used to differentially balance the packets. Example: For a route
          if there are 2 nexthops nh1 with weight 5 and nh2 with weight 1, then
          for every 5 packets that uses nh1, one packet will use nh2.
          In the first release, the above case is not supported. Only ECMP is
          supported.
          Default is 0 (for static routes).
      </column>
    </group>
   <group title="Status">
      <p>
        Status information to indicate the current state of the nexthop.
      </p>
      <column name="status" key="arp_resolved"
          type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
          Indicate if ARP is resolved for this entry. If the ARP entry is
          missing, this value is <code>false</code>
      </column>
      <column name="status" key="hw_configured"
          type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
          Indicate if nexthop programmed in the asic. If the ARP entry is
          missing, this value is <code>false</code>
      </column>
      <column name="status" key="error">
          Human readable error string.
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="BGP_Route" title="BGP Routes Information Base">
    <p>
      BGP local RIB.
    </p>
    <group title="BGP Routes">
      <column name="vrf">
        Reference to the VRF to which this route belongs.
      </column>
      <column name="prefix">
          IPv4 or IPv6 destination prefix and mask in the address/mask
          format. Example 192.168.0.0/16
      </column>
      <column name="address_family">
        Represents the address family for this entry.
        Default value is <code>ipv4</code>.
      </column>
      <column name="sub_address_family">
        Represents subsequent address family identifier such as unicast, multicast
        or MPLS VPN.
        Default is <code>unicast</code>.
      </column>
      <column name="distance">
          Administrative distance for the route entry.
          Default value is 0.
      </column>
      <column name="metric">
          This is the BGP Multi Exit Discriminator (MED) attribute used in best
          path selection.
          Default value is 0
      </column>
      <column name="bgp_nexthops">
          Represents nexthops for this entry. Each entry in the <ref table="BGP_Route"/>
          can have a reference to one or many(for ECMP) nexthop entries.
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Path attributes">
      <p>
          The <code>path_attributes</code> column contains key-value pairs that
          represent route attributes.
      </p>
      <column name="path_attributes" key="bgp_flags"
          type='{"type": "string"}'>
          Route status flags. Allowed values are <code>history</code>,
          <code>damped</code>,<code>multipath</code>,<code>valid</code>,
          <code>selected</code>
           Default value is 0.
      </column>
      <column name="path_attributes" key="bgp_as_path"
          type='{"type": "string"}'>
          List of AS path number for a route. Default is 0. Example: 200,300,400
      </column>
      <column name="path_attributes" key="bgp_origin"
          type='{"type": "string"}'>
          Indicates whether a route is <code>IGP</code>, <code>EGP</code>
          or <code>incomplete</code>.
          Default is incomplete.
      </column>
      <column name="path_attributes" key="bgp_loc_pref"
          type='{"type": "string"}'>
          Local preference path attribute. Used by BGP to influence in the
          best path selection.
          Default value is 0.
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="BGP_Nexthop" title="BGP Nexthops">
    <p>
      List of all nexthops used by BGP.
      Each entry in the BGP RIB can have a reference to one or
      many (for ECMP) nexthop entries.
    </p>
    <group title="Status">
      <column name="ip_address">
          IP address of the nexthop device.
      </column>
      <column name="type">
          Type of the nexthop.
          Default is <code>unicast</code>.
      </column>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="BGP_Router" title="BGP high level configuration">
    <group title="Configuration">
      BGP_router includes all bgp config related information. The entries are
      created on per asn basis.
      <column name="router_id">
      Specifies the router-id for given ASN.
      </column>
      <column name="networks">
      Announces networks for given bgp router.
      </column>
      <column name="maximum_paths">
      Number of paths BGP may install into the routing table. If not specified, BGP selects a
      single path.
      Default is 1.
      </column>
      <column name="timers" key="keepalive"
             type='{"type":"integer", "minInteger": 0, "maxInteger" : 65535}'>
      Specifies BGP keepalive time in seconds.
      Default is 60 seconds.
      </column>
      <column name="timers" key="holdtime"
              type='{"type":"integer", "minInteger": 0, "maxInteger" : 65535}'>
      Specifies BGP hold time in seconds.
      Default is 180 seconds.
      </column>
      <column name="redistribute">
      Allows redistribution of routes from various protocols.
      For example: static, connected. Enabling of redistribution protocols is not mutually
      exclusive.
      </column>
      <column name="always_compare_med">
      Compares MED (Multi-Exit Discriminitor) from different neighbors.
      Default is false.
      </column>
      <column name="deterministic_med">
      When enabled, selects the best-MED path among paths advertised from the neighboring AS.
      Default is false.
      </column>
      <column name="gr_stale_timer">
      Specifies the maximum time to hold onto restarting peer stale paths.
      Range: 1-3600 seconds.
      Default value is 360 seconds.
      </column>
      <column name="bgp_neighbors" keyname="ip_or_group_name">
        BGP neighbors or neighbor groups, keyed by IP for the former or any
	string name for the latter.
      </column>
    </group>
   <group title="Status">
      <column name="status" >
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.
      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="BGP_Neighbor" title="BGP Neighbors and Peer Groups">
    This table holds both BGP neighbors and BGP peer groups.  A boolean
    named is_peer_group identifies whether a specific entry is a bgp
    neighbor or a peer group.

    <group title="Neighbor Configuration">

      <column name="is_peer_group">
      This is a flag which identifies whether this specific entry is
      an individual BGP neighbor or is a BGP peer group.  A value
      of true implies a peer group.  Otherwise, the entry represents
      a BGP neighbor.  If the value is not set, it implies false.
      </column>

      <column name="description">
      This is an optional string which can be used for describing this entry.
      Default is empty.
      </column>

      <column name="shutdown">
      Specifies whether the neighbor has been administratively shut down.
      If not specified, the default is false.
      </column>

      <column name="bgp_peer_group">
      This column is used only if the entry is a BGP neighbor.  It represents
      the peer group this BGP neighbor is a member of.  Default is none.
      </column>

      <column name="local_interface">
      Reference to the corresponding interface.  This is used only for ipv6.
      Default is none.
      </column>

      <column name="remote_as">
      Peer AS number. For EBGP, the peer is in another AS, so the remote AS
      number must be different from the local router's AS number or BGP
      router asn. For IBGP, the peer is in the same AS, so the two AS
      numbers must be the same.
      Remote AS number. Range: 1-4294967295.
      </column>

      <column name="allow_as_in">
       Allow-as-in is the number of times BGP can allow an instance of AS
      to be in the AS_PATH.
      </column>

      <column name="local_as">
      To specify a different asn from BGP router asn to be used as local AS
      number in update messages to peers.
      Local AS number. Range: 1-4294967295.
      </column>

      <column name="weight">
      This is the weight for routes from this neighbor.
      </column>

      <column name="tcp_port_number">
      This is the BGP neighbor's tcp port number.  Default value is 179.
      </column>

      <column name="advertisement_interval">
      Minimum interval between sending BGP routing updates. Range: 0-600 seconds.
      </column>

      <column name="maximum_prefix_limit">
      Maximum number of prefixes that can be accepted on a BGP peer
      session. When the limit is exceeded, a system log message is logged.
      </column>

      <column name="capability">
      Advertise dynamic/ORF capabilities to the peer.
      </column>

      <column name="override_capability">
      Override capability negotiation result.
      </column>

      <column name="inbound_soft_reconfiguration">
      Allow inbound soft reconfiguration for this neighbor.
      </column>

      <column name="remove_private_as">
      Specifies whether private AS should be removed.
      If not specified, the default value is false.
      </column>

      <column name="passive">
      Indicates that open messages should NOT be sent to this neighbor.
      Default is false.
      </column>

      <column name="password">
      The password for this entry.
      </column>

      <column name="strict_capability_match">
      Strict capability negotiation match.
      </column>

      <column name="timers">
      BGP per neighbor timers - Connect timer/Keep-alive Interval.
      </column>

      <column name="route_maps">
      Name and direction of the route maps.
      </column>

      <column name="route_maps" key="in">
      Map associated with incoming routes.
      </column>

      <column name="route_maps" key="out">
      Map associated with outbound routes.
      </column>

    </group>

   <group title="Status">
      <column name="status">
      These values describe various status information about this
      BGP neighbor or BGP Peer group entry.
      </column>
   </group>

   <group title="BGP Neighbor or Peer group Status Info">
      <p>
        The <code>status</code> column contains one or more
        informational entries indicating various status
        values for this BGP neighbor.
      </p>
      <column name="status" key="bgp_peer_state">
          This represents the BGP neighbor state at this specific
          instance in time.  The value can be one of Idle, Connect,
          Active, OpenSent, OpenConfirm, Established, Clearing or
          Deleted and can change any time.  Default is Idle.
      </column>
   </group>

   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config">
      </column>

      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>

   <group title="BGP Neighbor Statistics">
     <p>
       The <code>statistics</code> column contains various counters
       about this BGP neighbor.
     </p>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_established_count">
      This indicates the number of times peers have been established.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_dropped_count">
      This indicates the number of times peers have been dropped
      from the established state.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_open_in_count">
      This indicates how many times an open message has been received.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_open_out_count">
      This indicates how many times an open message has been sent.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_update_in_count">
      This indicates how many times an update message has been received.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_update_out_count">
      This indicates how many times an update message has been sent.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_keepalive_in_count">
      This indicates how many times a keepalive message has been received.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_keepalive_out_count">
      This indicates how many times a keepalive message has been sent.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_notify_in_count">
      This indicates how many times a notify message has been received.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_notify_out_count">
      This indicates how many times a notify message has been sent.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_refresh_in_count">
      This indicates how many times a frefresh message has been received.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_refresh_out_count">
      This indicates how many times a refresh message has been sent.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_dynamic_cap_in_count">
      This indicates how many times a dynamic cap message has been received.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_dynamic_cap_out_count">
      This indicates how many times a dynamic cap message has been sent.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_uptime">
      This indicates how long since peer has been in the established state,
      or since the last route update was received.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_readtime">
      This indicates the last time an update or keepalive message has been
      received.
      </column>
      <column name="statistics" key="bgp_peer_resettime">
      Indicates the last time peer was reset.
      </column>
   </group>

  </table>

  <table name="Neighbor" title="L2 Neighbors">
    <p>
      List of all the connected neighbors.
    </p>
    <group title="Neighbor information">
      <column name="vrf">
        Reference to the VRF table, to which this neighbor belongs.
      </column>
      <column name="ip_address">
        The IPv4 address or the IPv6 address of neighbor
      </column>
      <column name="address_family">
          Address family of the neighbor.
      </column>
      <column name="mac">
        MAC address learned for this neighbor.
      </column>
      <column name="port">
         Port on which this neighbor was learned.
      </column>
      <column name="state">
        Current state of the neighbor entry.
      </column>
      <column name="status" key="dp_hit"
          type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
          Indicates if there is active traffic to the neighbor. This value
          is periodically updated. If the value is set to <code>false</code>,
          it indicates that there was no traffic to this neighbor recently.
          Default is <code>true</code>
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="VLAN" title="Virtual Local Area Network">
    <group title="Configuration">
      <column name="name">
        VLAN name.  Should be alphanumeric and no more than about 8 bytes long.
      </column>
      <column name="id">
        The ID of this VLAN.
      </column>
      <column name="description">
        User provided description of this VLAN.
      </column>
      <column name="admin">
        Administratively configured state of this VLAN.
        Default is down if not specified.
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Hardware VLAN Configuration">
      <column name="hw_vlan_config">
          Key-value pairs that represent the configuration passed down to hardware.
      </column>
      <column name="hw_vlan_config" key="enable">
        The possible values are "true" and "false".
      </column>
    </group>
   <group title="VLAN Status">
      <column name="oper_state">
        Operational state of this VLAN.
      </column>
      <column name="oper_state_reason">
        Human readable reason for the operational state of this VLAN.
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Internal VLAN Config">
      <p>
          Information about how this VLAN is used internally by the system.
          VLAN could be used for L3 interface, sflow, etc.
      </p>
      <column name="internal_usage">
          Key-value pairs that represent how this VLAN is used internally by the
          system.
      </column>
      <column name="internal_usage" key="l3port">
          VLAN is used internally by ASIC to configure L3 behavior of the port.
          The value is the port name that uses this VLAN.
      </column>
    </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

 <table name="Port" table="Port or bond configuration.">
    <p>A port within a <ref table="Bridge"/>.</p>
    <p>Most commonly, a port has exactly one ``interface,'' pointed to by its
    <ref column="interfaces"/> column.  Such a port logically
    corresponds to a port on a physical Ethernet switch.  A port
    with more than one interface is a ``bonded port'' (see
    <ref group="Bonding Configuration"/>).</p>
    <p>Some properties that one might think as belonging to a port are actually
    part of the port's <ref table="Interface"/> members.</p>

    <p>
        If port has an IP address, then it becomes L3 and might participate
        in VRFs. Unless referenced interface has an "internal" type, L3 port
        can not participate in the bridge.
        "internal" ports that basically represent VLAN interfaces may be
        referenced by both Bridge and VRF.
    </p>

    <column name="name">
      Port name.  Should be alphanumeric and no more than about 8
      bytes long.  May be the same as the interface name, for
      non-bonded ports.  Must otherwise be unique among the names of
      ports, interfaces, and bridges on a host.
    </column>

    <column name="interfaces">
      The port's interfaces.  If there is more than one, this is a
      bonded Port. A maximum of 8 interfaces can be assigned to a port.
    </column>

    <column name="admin">
      The administrative state of the Port configured by user. The port admin
      state determines the hardware configuration based on the business logic.
      When port "admin" is configured down the interface(s) associated
      with the port should force their hardware configuration to down. By
      default the port is up.
    </column>

    <group title="Hardware Port Configuration">
      <p>
        The following fields are not meant to be configured by the user,
        but rather by <code>portd</code> daemon that is responsible to consider
        user configuration and business logic in order to determine
        hardware configuration.
      </p>

      <column name="hw_config">
        Key-value pairs that represent the configuration passed down to hardware.
      </column>
      <column name="hw_config" key="enable"
              type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
        The possible values are "true" and "false".
      </column>
      <column name="hw_config" key="internal-vlan">
        The VLAN associated with l3 interfaces.
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="VLAN Configuration">
      <p>Bridge ports support the following types of VLAN configuration:</p>
      <dl>
        <dt>trunk</dt>
        <dd>
          <p>
            A trunk port carries packets on one or more VLANs specified
            in the <ref column="trunks"/> column (or all VLANs defined in
            <ref table="VLAN"/> table if trunks is empty or not specified).
            A packet that ingresses on a trunk port is in the VLAN
            specified in its 802.1Q header, or VLAN 1 if the packet has no
            802.1Q header.  A packet that egresses through a trunk port will
            have an 802.1Q header if it has a nonzero VLAN ID.
          </p>

          <p>
            Any packet that ingresses on a trunk port tagged with a VLAN that
            the port does not trunk is dropped.
          </p>
        </dd>

        <dt>access</dt>
        <dd>
          <p>
            An access port carries packets on exactly one VLAN specified in the
            <ref column="tag"/> column.  Packets egressing on an access port
            have no 802.1Q header.
          </p>

          <p>
            Any packet with an 802.1Q header with a nonzero VLAN ID that
            ingresses on an access port is dropped, regardless of whether the
            VLAN ID in the header is the access port's VLAN ID.
          </p>
        </dd>

        <dt>native-tagged</dt>
        <dd>
          A native-tagged port resembles a trunk port, with the exception that
          a packet without an 802.1Q header that ingresses on a native-tagged
          port is in the ``native VLAN'' (specified in the <ref column="tag"/>
          column).
        </dd>

        <dt>native-untagged</dt>
        <dd>
          A native-untagged port resembles a native-tagged port, with the
          exception that a packet that egresses on a native-untagged port in
          the native VLAN will not have an 802.1Q header.
        </dd>
      </dl>
      <p>
        A packet will only egress through bridge ports that carry the VLAN of
        the packet, as described by the rules above.
      </p>

      <column name="vlan_mode">
        <p>
          The VLAN mode of the port, as described above.  When this column is
          empty, a default mode is selected as follows:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            If <ref column="tag"/> contains a value, the port is an access
            port.  The <ref column="trunks"/> column should be empty.
          </li>
          <li>
            Otherwise, the port is a trunk port.  The <ref column="trunks"/>
            column value is honored if it is present.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </column>

      <column name="tag">
        <p>
          For an access port, the port's implicitly tagged VLAN.  For a
          native-tagged or native-untagged port, the port's native VLAN.  Must
          be empty if this is a trunk port.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="trunks">
        <p>
          For a trunk, native-tagged, or native-untagged port, the 802.1Q VLAN
          or VLANs that this port trunks; if it is empty, then the port trunks
          all VLANs defined in the <ref table="VLAN"/> table.  Must be empty
          if this is an access port.
        </p>
        <p>
          A native-tagged or native-untagged port always trunks its native
          VLAN, regardless of whether <ref column="trunks"/> includes that
          VLAN.
        </p>
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Bonding Configuration">
      <p>A port that has more than one interface is a ``bonded port.'' Bonding
      allows for load balancing and fail-over.</p>

      <p>
        The following modes (bond_mode) require the upstream switch to support
        802.3ad with successful LACP negotiation.</p>

      <p>These columns apply only to bonded ports.  Their values are otherwise
          ignored.</p>

      <column name="bond_mode"> <p>The type of bonding used for a bonded port.
              Defaults to <code>l3-src-dst-hash</code> if not assigned.  </p>
      </column>

      <group title="LACP Configuration">
        <p>
          LACP, the Link Aggregation Control Protocol, is an IEEE standard that
          allows switches to automatically detect that they are connected by
          multiple links and aggregate across those links.  These settings
          control LACP behavior.
        </p>

        <column name="lacp">
          Configures LACP on this port.  LACP allows directly connected
          switches to negotiate which links may be bonded.  LACP may be enabled
          on non-bonded ports for the benefit of any switches they may be
          connected to.  <code>active</code> ports are allowed to initiate LACP
          negotiations.  <code>passive</code> ports are allowed to participate
          in LACP negotiations initiated by a remote switch, but not allowed to
          initiate such negotiations themselves.  If LACP is enabled on a port
          whose partner switch does not support LACP, the bond will be
          disabled. Defaults to <code>off</code> if unset.
        </column>

        <column name="other_config" key="lacp-system-id">
          The LACP system ID of this <ref table="Port"/>.  The system ID of a
          LACP bond is used to identify itself to its partners.  Must be a
          nonzero MAC address. Defaults to the bridge Ethernet address if
          unset.
        </column>

        <column name="other_config" key="lacp-system-priority"
                type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1, "maxInteger": 65535}'>
          The LACP system priority of this <ref table="Port"/>.  In LACP
          negotiations, link status decisions are made by the system with the
          numerically lower priority.
        </column>

        <column name="other_config" key="lacp-time"
          type='{"type": "string", "enum": ["set", ["fast", "slow"]]}'>
          <p>
            The LACP timing which should be used on this <ref table="Port"/>.
            By default <code>slow</code> is used.  When configured to be
            <code>fast</code> LACP heartbeats are requested at a rate of once
            per second causing connectivity problems to be detected more
            quickly.  In <code>slow</code> mode, heartbeats are requested at a
            rate of once every 30 seconds.
          </p>
        </column>
      </group>
    </group>
   <group title="L3 Configuration">
       <column name="ip4_address">
        The IPv4 address and subnet mask in the address/mask format.
        This is the primary IP address.
      </column>
       <column name="ip4_address_secondary">
        This is a list of secondary IPv4 addresses and subnet mask
        in the address/mask format.
      </column>
       <column name="ip6_address">
        The IPv6 address and subnet mask in the address/mask format.
        This is the primary IPv6 address.
      </column>
       <column name="ip6_address_secondary">
        This is a list of secondary IPv6 addresses and subnet mask
        in the address/mask format.
      </column>
   </group>

   <group title="Other Features">
      <column name="mac">
        The MAC address to use for this port for the purpose of choosing the
        bridge's MAC address.  This column does not necessarily reflect the
        port's actual MAC address, nor will setting it change the port's actual
        MAC address.
      </column>

   </group>

    <group title="Port Status">
      <p>
        Status information about ports attached to bridges.
      </p>
      <column name="status">
        Key-value pairs that report port status.
      </column>
      <column name="status" key="bond_hw_handle">
        Unique identifier of the LAG from the data path's perspective.
        This key value should be treated as opaque handle by application
        daemons while updating LAG member interfaces in hardware.
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status">
        Key-value pairs that report lacp-specific port status.
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status" key="bond_speed">
        Speed of interfaces operating in lag.
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status" key="bond_status">
        Operational status of LAG. The values are "ok" (bond is functional)
        "down" (bond isn't functional), and "defaulted" (remote LACP not
        operating, using one interface in non-LACP mode).
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status" key="bond_status_reason">
        String identifying the reason why the bond_status is "down".
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Port Statistics">
      <p>
        Key-value pairs that report port statistics.  The update period
        is controlled by <ref column="other_config"
        key="stats-update-interval"/> in the <ref table="System"/> table.
      </p>
    </group>

    <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config"/>
      <column name="external_ids"/>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Interface" title="One physical network device in a Port.">
    An interface within a <ref table="Port"/>.

    <group title="Core Features">
      <column name="name">
        Interface name.  Should be alphanumeric and no more than about 8 bytes
        long.  May be the same as the port name, for non-bonded ports.  Must
        otherwise be unique among the names of ports, interfaces, and bridges
        on a host.
      </column>

    </group>

    <group title="System-Specific Details">
      <column name="type">
        <p>
          The interface type, one of:
        </p>

        <dl>
          <dt><code>system</code></dt>
          <dd>An ordinary network device, e.g. <code>eth0</code> on Linux.
          Sometimes referred to as ``external interfaces'' since they are
          generally connected to hardware external to that on which the Open
          Halon is running.  The empty string is a synonym for
          <code>system</code>.</dd>

          <dt><code>internal</code></dt>
          <dd>A simulated network device that sends and receives traffic.  An
          internal interface whose <ref column="name"/> is the same as its
          bridge's <ref table="System" column="name"/> is called the
          ``local interface.''  It does not make sense to bond an internal
          interface, so the terms ``port'' and ``interface'' are often used
          imprecisely for internal interfaces.</dd>
       </dl>
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Interface Status">
      <p>
        Status information about interfaces attached to bridges, updated every
        5 seconds.  Not all interfaces have all of these properties; virtual
        interfaces don't have a link speed, for example.  Non-applicable
        columns will have empty values.
      </p>
      <column name="admin_state">
        <p>
          The administrative state of the physical network link.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="error">
        If the configuration of the <ref table="Interface"/> failed,
        Open Halon sets this column to an error
        description in human readable form.  Otherwise, Open Halon clears
        this column.
      </column>
      <column name="mac_in_use">
        The MAC address in use by this <ref table="Interface"/>.
      </column>

      <column name="link_state">
        <p>
          The observed state of the physical network link.  This is ordinarily
          the link's carrier status.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="link_resets">
        <p>
          The number of times Open Halon has observed the
          <ref column="link_state"/> of this <ref table="Interface"/> change.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="link_speed">
        <p>
          The negotiated speed of the physical network link in bits per second.
          Valid values are positive integers greater than 0.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="duplex">
        <p>
          The duplex mode of the physical network link.
        </p>
      </column>
      <column name="pause">
        <p>
          The status of the Ethernet PAUSE (link-level flow control)
          mode of the physical network link.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="mtu">
        <p>
          The MTU (maximum transmission unit); i.e. the largest
          amount of data that can fit into a single Ethernet frame.
          The standard Ethernet MTU is 1500 bytes.  Some physical media
          and many kinds of virtual interfaces can be configured with
          higher MTUs.
        </p>
        <p>
          This column will be empty for an interface that does not
          have an MTU as, for example, some kinds of tunnels do not.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="lacp_current">
        Boolean value indicating LACP status for this interface.  If true, this
        interface has current LACP information about its LACP partner.  This
        information may be used to monitor the health of interfaces in a LACP
        enabled port.  This column will be empty if LACP is not enabled.
      </column>

      <column name="lacp_status">
        Key-value pairs that report LACP protocol status.
      </column>

      <column name="lacp_status" key="actor_system_id">
        The LACP actor system ID in the form of priority and mac address tuple.
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status" key="actor_port_id">
        The LACP actor port ID in the form of priority and port number tuple.
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status" key="actor_key">
        The LACP actor key in use.
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status" key="actor_state">
        The LACP actor protocol state information in an abbreviated form
        reporting status/state bit values. For example,
            (Actv:1,TmOut:1,Aggr:1,Sync:1,Col:1,Dist:1,Def:0,Exp:0)
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status" key="partner_system_id">
        The LACP partner system ID in the form of priority and mac address tuple.
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status" key="partner_port_id">
        The LACP partner port ID in the form of priority and port number tuple.
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status" key="partner_key">
        The LACP partner key in use.
      </column>
      <column name="lacp_status" key="partner_state">
        The LACP partner protocol state information in an abbreviated form
        reporting status/state bit values. For example,
            (Actv:1,TmOut:1,Aggr:1,Sync:1,Col:1,Dist:1,Def:0,Exp:0)
      </column>

      <column name="hw_bond_config">
        Key-value pairs that configure the interface as a member of bond.
      </column>
      <column name="hw_bond_config" key="bond_hw_handle">
        Identifies the LAG to which this interface should be attached in
        hardware. This value is directly copied from
        <ref table="Port" column="status" key="bond_hw_handle"/>.
      </column>
      <column name="hw_bond_config" key="rx_enabled">
        A state flag to indicate that this interface is attached to a
        hardware LAG and receive logic is enabled.
        Defaults to <code>false</code> if unset.
      </column>
      <column name="hw_bond_config" key="tx_enabled">
        A state flag to indicate that the transmit logic is enabled for this
        interface in hardware LAG.
        Defaults to <code>false</code> if unset.
      </column>

      <column name="lldp_neighbor_info">
        This column includes a map of keys:values of neighbors as discovered
        by LLDP.
      </column>

      <column name="status">
        Key-value pairs that report port status.  Supported status values are
        <ref column="type"/>-dependent; some interfaces may not have a valid
        <ref column="status" key="driver_name"/>, for example.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="driver_name">
        The name of the device driver controlling the network adapter.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="driver_version">
        The version string of the device driver controlling the network
        adapter.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="firmware_version">
        The version string of the network adapter's firmware, if available.
      </column>

    <group title="LLDP status info">
      <column name="status" key="lldp_local_port_vlan">
        Information about port VLAN config.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="lldp_local_port_description">
        Description of LLDP port in alpha-numeric format.
      </column>
    </group>

    </group>

    <group title="Module Information">
      <p>
        Information about the pluggable module inserted into the physical interface socket.
      </p>

      <column name="pm_info">
        Key-value pairs that report pluggable module information.
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="connector">
        The type of pluggable module connector inserted into the socket.
        The possible values are "absent", "unknown", "SFP_RJ45", "SFP_SX", "SFP_LX",
        "SFP_CX", "SFP_SR", "SFP_LR", "SFP_LRM", "SFP_DAC", "SFP_FC", "QSFP_CR4",
        "QSFP_SR4" and "QSFP_LR4".
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="connector_status">
        The status of the connector to indicate whether it is supported by the hardware platform.
        The possible values are "unrecognized", "unsupported" and "supported".
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="supported_speeds">
        The list of speeds, in megabits per second, supported by this pluggable module.
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="cable_technology">
        This indicates whether a copper pluggable module is active or passive.
        The possible values are "active" and "passive".
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="cable_length">
        The length of the cable in meters. This is only applicable to transceivers
        with built-in cable or the maximum cable length for a transceiver restricted
        by length.
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="max_speed">
        The maximum speed supported by the transceiver, in units of megabits per second.
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="power_mode">
        The power mode for the pluggable module. The possible values are "low" or "high".
        This typically applies to QSFP pluggable modules.
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="vendor_name">
        The name of the vendor of the module.
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="vendor_oui">
        The Organizationally Unique Identifier (OUI) of the module vendor.
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="vendor_part_number">
        The vendor's module part number.
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="vendor_revision">
        The vendor's module revision number.
      </column>
      <column name="pm_info" key="vendor_serial_number">
        The vendor's module serial number.
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Statistics">
      <p>
        Key-value pairs that report interface statistics.  The current
        implementation updates these counters periodically.  The update period
        is controlled by <ref column="other_config"
        key="stats-update-interval"/> in the <ref table="System"/> table.
     </p>
      <p>
        If an interface does not support a
        given statistic, then that pair is omitted.
      </p>
      <group title="Statistics: Successful transmit and receive counters">
        <column name="statistics" key="rx_packets">
          Number of received packets.
        </column>
        <column name="statistics" key="rx_bytes">
          Number of received bytes.
        </column>
        <column name="statistics" key="tx_packets">
          Number of transmitted packets.
        </column>
        <column name="statistics" key="tx_bytes">
          Number of transmitted bytes.
        </column>
      </group>
      <group title="Statistics: Receive errors">
        <column name="statistics" key="rx_dropped">
          Number of packets dropped by RX.
        </column>
        <column name="statistics" key="rx_frame_err">
          Number of frame alignment errors.
        </column>
        <column name="statistics" key="rx_over_err">
          Number of packets with RX overrun.
        </column>
        <column name="statistics" key="rx_crc_err">
          Number of CRC errors.
        </column>
        <column name="statistics" key="rx_errors">
          Total number of receive errors, greater than or equal to the sum of
          the above.
        </column>
      </group>
      <group title="Statistics: Transmit errors">
        <column name="statistics" key="tx_dropped">
          Number of packets dropped by TX.
        </column>
        <column name="statistics" key="collisions">
          Number of collisions.
        </column>
        <column name="statistics" key="tx_errors">
          Total number of transmit errors, greater than or equal to the sum of
          the above.
        </column>
      </group>
      <group title="LLDP Interface Level Statistics">
        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_tx">
          Number of lldp packets transmitted.
        </column>
        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_tx_len_err">
          Number of lldp packet transmit error because of length.
        </column>
        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_rx">
          Number of lldp packets received.
        </column>
        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_rx_err">
          Number of lldp packets received with one or more detectable errors.
        </column>
        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_rx_discard">
          Number of lldp packet received and discarded because of missing,
          out-of-order or incorrect TLVs.
        </column>
        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_rx_tlv_discard">
          Number of lldp TLVs discarded because of errors.
        </column>
        <column name="lldp_statistics" key="lldp_rx_tlv_unknown">
          Number of lldp TLVs discarded because of unknown tlv.
        </column>
      </group>
    </group>

    <group title="Bonding Configuration">
      <column name="other_config" key="lacp-port-id"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1, "maxInteger": 65535}'>
        The LACP port ID of this <ref table="Interface"/>.  Port IDs are
        used in LACP negotiations to identify individual ports
        participating in a bond.
      </column>

      <column name="other_config" key="lacp-port-priority"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 1, "maxInteger": 65535}'>
        The LACP port priority of this <ref table="Interface"/>.  In LACP
        negotiations <ref table="Interface"/>s with numerically lower
        priorities are preferred for aggregation.
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="User Configuration">
    <p>
      The following fields are meant to be configured by the user.
      It represents the configuration of the interface in the bridge.
    </p>

    <column name="user_config">
      Key-value pairs that stores the user configuration of <ref table="Interface"/>.
    </column>
    <column name="user_config" key="admin">
      The user-configured administrative state of <ref table="Interface"/>.
      The possible values are "up" and "down".  Default is "down" if not specified.
    </column>
    <column name="user_config" key="autoneg">
      The user-configured auto-negotiation state of <ref table="Interface"/>.
      The possible values are "default", "on", and "off".
    </column>
    <column name="user_config" key="speeds">
      The list of user-configured interface speeds in megabits per second.
      When autoneg is disabled, the first speed value in the list is applied.
    </column>
    <column name="user_config" key="duplex">
      The user-configured duplex mode of <ref table="Interface"/>.
      The possible values are "half" and "full".
    </column>
    <column name="user_config" key="pause">
      The user-configured Ethernet PAUSE (link-level flow control) mode
      of <ref table="Interface"/>. The possible values are "none", "rx", "tx", and "rxtx".
    </column>
    <column name="user_config" key="mtu">
      The user-configured MTU of <ref table="Interface"/>.
    </column>
    <column name="user_config" key="lane_split">
      The user-configured split mode of <ref table="Interface"/>.
      This is only applicable if an interface can be split into
      multiple interfaces, e.g. QSFP+ ports.
      The possible values are "split" and "no-split".
    </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Hardware Interface Configuration">
    <p>
      The following fields are not meant to be configured by the user,
      but rather by <code>intfd</code> daemon that is responsible to consider
      user configuration or the port admin_state configuration and business
      logic in order to determine hardware configuration. When port associated
      with the interface is configured to down the hardware configuration is
      forced to down.
    </p>

    <column name="hw_intf_config">
      Key-value pairs that represent the configuration passed down to hardware.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_config" key="enable">
      The possible values are "true" and "false".
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_config" key="autoneg">
      The possible values are "on" and "off".
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_config" key="speeds">
      The list of possible interface speeds, in megabits per second.
      If autoneg is true, this is the list of advertised speeds.
      If not, the first speed in the list is the fixed speed of <ref table="Interface"/>.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_config" key="duplex">
      The possible values are "half" and "full".
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_config" key="pause">
      The possible values are "none", "rx", "tx", and "rxtx".
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_config" key="mtu">
      Maximum transmission unit (MTU) of <ref table="Interface"/>.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_config" key="interface_type">
      Physical layer interface type of <ref table="Interface"/>.
      The possible values are "unknown", "backplane", "1GBASE_SX", "1GBASE_T",
      "10GBASE_CR", "10GBASE_SR", "10GBASE_LR", "10GBASE_LRM", "40GBASE_CR4",
      "40GBASE_SR4" and "40GBASE_LR4".
    </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Hardware Interface Information">
    <p>
      The following fields describes the hardware information of <ref table="Interface"/>.
      These values do not change through the life of the system.
    </p>

    <column name="hw_intf_info">
      Key-value pairs that show the information about a physical interface.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="switch_unit">
      The hardware switch chip unit identifier.
      This value is applicable only to interfaces on physical switch devices.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="switch_intf_id">
      The hardware switch chip interface identifier.
      This value is applicable only to interfaces on physical switch devices.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="mac_addr">
      The MAC Address for the interface.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="max_speed">
      The maximum speed of the interface in units of megabits per second.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="speeds">
      The list of supported speeds of the interface in units of megabits per second.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="connector">
      The form factor of the interface socket.
      The possible values are "SFP_PLUS" and "QSFP_PLUS".
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="pluggable">
      Boolean value indicating whether or not the interface has a fixed connector or
      a pluggable module socket.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="capability_enet1G">
      Boolean value indicating whether or not the interface supports Ethernet
      1G speed.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="capability_enet10G">
      Boolean value indicating whether or not the interface supports Ethernet
      10G speed.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="capability_enet40G">
      Boolean value indicating whether or not the interface supports Ethernet
      40G speed.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="capability_split_4">
      Boolean value indicating whether or not the interface supports being
      split into four split ports. For example, a QSFP+ port can run as a
      single port or can be split into four 10G split ports using a QSFP+
      splitter cable.
    </column>
    <column name="hw_intf_info" key="bridge"
      type='{"type": "boolean"}'>
      Boolean value indicating interface is a `bridge' interface which is
      created for every bridge instance. The `bridge' interface receives all
      VLAN traffic and distributes to the vlan interfaces based on the VLAN
      tags. The default value is `false'
    </column>
    <column name="split_parent">
      For a split child interface, this is the reference to the parent <ref table="Interface"/>.
    </column>
    <column name="split_children">
      For a split parent interface, this is the reference to the list of children <ref table="Interface"/>s.
    </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config"/>
    <group title="LLDP Interface configurations">
        <column name="other_config" key="lldp_enable_dir"
          type='{"type": "string", "enum": ["set", ["off", "rx", "tx", "rxtx"]]}'>
          <p>
            LLDP interface level config.
          </p>
        </column>
    </group>
      <column name="external_ids"/>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Fan" title="Fans on various subsystems">
    <group title="Core Features">
      <column name="name">
      </column>
    </group>
    <group title="Status">
      <column name="speed">
      </column>
      <column name="direction">
      </column>
      <column name="rpm" >
      </column>
      <column name="status" >
      </column>
    </group>
    <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="LED" title="LEDs on various subsystems">
    <group title="Configuration">
      <column name="id">
      </column>
      <column name="state">
      </column>
    </group>
   <group title="Status">
      <column name="status" >
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Temp_sensor" title="Temperature sensors">
      <column name="name">
        Logical name of the temperature sensor, including the subsystem name and
        numeric identifier of the temperature sensor.
      </column>
      <column name="location">
        Descriptive text for the physical location of the temperature sensor
        relative to the subsystem.
      </column>
    <group title="Readings">
      <column name="temperature">
        Current temperature reading, in milidegrees Celcius.
      </column>
      <column name="min">
        Historic minimum (since last restart of tempd process), in milidegrees
        Celcius.
      </column>
      <column name="max">
        Historic maximum (since last restart of tempd process), in milidegrees
        Celcius.
      </column>
    </group>
   <group title="Status">
      <column name="status"
        type='{"type": "string", "enum": ["set", ["uninitialized", "normal", "min", "max", "low_critical", "critical","fault","emergency"]]}'>
        Results of evaluation of the current temperature against the sensor's
        threshold values.
      </column>
      <column name="fan_state"
        type='{"type": "string", "enum": ["set", ["normal", "medium", "fast", "max"]]}'>
        Recommended minimum fan setting based on current temperature. The fand
        process should choose the worst-case sensor fan_state when determining
        the fan setting for the subsystem.
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Power_supply" title="Power supplies">
      <column name="name">
      </column>
   <group title="Status">
      <column name="status" >
      </column>
   </group>
   <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="other_config">
      </column>
      <column name="external_ids">
      </column>
   </group>
  </table>

  <table name="Radius_Server" title="Radius server configuration">
      These radius servers are being used for authenticating when users
      wants to login to the box.

      <column name="ip_address">
          IP address of the radius server configured.
      </column>

      <column name="priority">
          Specifies the order in which radius servers are configured on the switch.
      </column>

      <column name="udp_port" >
          Specifies the udp port number for authentication. Default udp port
          number for authentication is 1812.
      </column>

      <column name="passkey" >
          Specifies the passkey between radius client and radius server
          for authentication. Default passkey is testing123-1.
      </column>

      <column name="timeout" >
          Specifies the timeout between authentication requests to radius server.
          Default timeout is 5 seconds.
      </column>

      <column name="retries" >
          Specifies the number of retries to radius server if there is no response.
          Default retry value is 1.
      </column>
  </table>

  <table name="Manager" title="OVSDB management connection.">
    <p>
      Configuration for a database connection to an Open Halon database
      (OVSDB) client.
    </p>

    <p>
      This table primarily configures the Open Halon database
      (<code>ovsdb-server</code>), not the Open Halon switch
      (<code>ovs-vswitchd</code>).  The switch does read the table to determine
      what connections should be treated as in-band.
    </p>

    <p>
      The Open Halon database server can initiate and maintain active
      connections to remote clients.  It can also listen for database
      connections.
    </p>

    <group title="Core Features">
      <column name="target">
        <p>Connection method for managers.</p>
        <p>
          The following connection methods are currently supported:
        </p>
        <dl>
          <dt><code>ssl:<var>ip</var></code>[<code>:<var>port</var></code>]</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              The specified SSL <var>port</var> on the host at the given
              <var>ip</var>, which must be expressed as an IP address
              (not a DNS name).  The <ref table="System"
              column="ssl"/> column in the <ref table="System"/>
              table must point to a valid SSL configuration when this
              form is used.
            </p>
            <p>
              If <var>port</var> is not specified, it currently defaults
              to 6632.  In the future, the default will change to 6640,
              which is the IANA-defined value.
            </p>
            <p>
              SSL support is an optional feature that is not always
              built as part of Open Halon.
            </p>
          </dd>

          <dt><code>tcp:<var>ip</var></code>[<code>:<var>port</var></code>]</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              The specified TCP <var>port</var> on the host at the given
              <var>ip</var>, which must be expressed as an IP address (not a
              DNS name), where <var>ip</var> can be IPv4 or IPv6 address.  If
              <var>ip</var> is an IPv6 address, wrap it in square brackets,
              e.g. <code>tcp:[::1]:6632</code>.
            </p>
            <p>
              If <var>port</var> is not specified, it currently defaults
              to 6632.  In the future, the default will change to 6640,
              which is the IANA-defined value.
            </p>
          </dd>
          <dt><code>pssl:</code>[<var>port</var>][<code>:<var>ip</var></code>]</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              Listens for SSL connections on the specified TCP <var>port</var>.
              Specify 0 for <var>port</var> to have the kernel automatically
              choose an available port.  If <var>ip</var>, which must be
              expressed as an IP address (not a DNS name), is specified, then
              connections are restricted to the specified local IP address
              (either IPv4 or IPv6 address).  If <var>ip</var> is an IPv6
              address, wrap in square brackets,
              e.g. <code>pssl:6632:[::1]</code>.  If <var>ip</var> is not
              specified then it listens only on IPv4 (but not IPv6) addresses.
              The <ref table="System" column="ssl"/> column in the <ref
              table="System"/> table must point to a valid SSL
              configuration when this form is used.
            </p>
            <p>
              If <var>port</var> is not specified, it currently defaults
              to 6632.  In the future, the default will change to 6640,
              which is the IANA-defined value.
            </p>
            <p>
              SSL support is an optional feature that is not always built as
              part of Open Halon.
            </p>
          </dd>
          <dt><code>ptcp:</code>[<var>port</var>][<code>:<var>ip</var></code>]</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              Listens for connections on the specified TCP <var>port</var>.
              Specify 0 for <var>port</var> to have the kernel automatically
              choose an available port.  If <var>ip</var>, which must be
              expressed as an IP address (not a DNS name), is specified, then
              connections are restricted to the specified local IP address
              (either IPv4 or IPv6 address).  If <var>ip</var> is an IPv6
              address, wrap it in square brackets,
              e.g. <code>ptcp:6632:[::1]</code>.  If <var>ip</var> is not
              specified then it listens only on IPv4 addresses.
            </p>
            <p>
              If <var>port</var> is not specified, it currently defaults
              to 6632.  In the future, the default will change to 6640,
              which is the IANA-defined value.
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dl>
        <p>When multiple managers are configured, the <ref column="target"/>
        values must be unique.  Duplicate <ref column="target"/> values yield
        unspecified results.</p>
      </column>

      <column name="connection_mode">
        <p>
          If it is specified, this setting must be one of the following strings
          that describes how Open Halon contacts this OVSDB client over the
          network:
        </p>

        <dl>
          <dt><code>in-band</code></dt>
          <dd>
            In this mode, this connection's traffic travels over a bridge
            managed by Open Halon.  With this setting, Open Halon allows
            traffic to and from the client regardless of the contents of the
            OpenFlow flow table.  (Otherwise, Open Halon would never be able
            to connect to the client, because it did not have a flow to enable
            it.)  This is the most common connection mode because it is not
            necessary to maintain two independent networks.
          </dd>
          <dt><code>out-of-band</code></dt>
          <dd>
            In this mode, the client's traffic uses a control network separate
            from that managed by Open Halon, that is, Open Halon does not
            use any of its own network devices to communicate with the client.
            The control network must be configured separately, before or after
            <code>pswitchd</code> is started.
          </dd>
        </dl>

        <p>
          If not specified, the default is implementation-specific.
        </p>
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Client Failure Detection and Handling">
      <column name="max_backoff">
        Maximum number of milliseconds to wait between connection attempts.
        Default is implementation-specific.
      </column>

      <column name="inactivity_probe">
        Maximum number of milliseconds of idle time on connection to the client
        before sending an inactivity probe message.  If Open Halon does not
        communicate with the client for the specified number of seconds, it
        will send a probe.  If a response is not received for the same
        additional amount of time, Open Halon assumes the connection has been
        broken and attempts to reconnect.  Default is implementation-specific.
        A value of 0 disables inactivity probes.
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Status">
      <column name="is_connected">
        <code>true</code> if currently connected to this manager,
        <code>false</code> otherwise.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="last_error">
        A human-readable description of the last error on the connection
        to the manager; i.e. <code>strerror(errno)</code>.  This key
        will exist only if an error has occurred.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="state"
              type='{"type": "string", "enum": ["set", ["VOID", "BACKOFF", "CONNECTING", "ACTIVE", "IDLE"]]}'>
        <p>
          The state of the connection to the manager:
        </p>
        <dl>
          <dt><code>VOID</code></dt>
          <dd>Connection is disabled.</dd>

          <dt><code>BACKOFF</code></dt>
          <dd>Attempting to reconnect at an increasing period.</dd>

          <dt><code>CONNECTING</code></dt>
          <dd>Attempting to connect.</dd>

          <dt><code>ACTIVE</code></dt>
          <dd>Connected, remote host responsive.</dd>

          <dt><code>IDLE</code></dt>
          <dd>Connection is idle.  Waiting for response to keep-alive.</dd>
        </dl>
        <p>
          These values may change in the future.  They are provided only for
          human consumption.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="sec_since_connect"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 0}'>
        The amount of time since this manager last successfully connected
        to the database (in seconds). Value is empty if manager has never
        successfully connected.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="sec_since_disconnect"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 0}'>
        The amount of time since this manager last disconnected from the
        database (in seconds). Value is empty if manager has never
        disconnected.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="locks_held">
        Space-separated list of the names of OVSDB locks that the connection
        holds.  Omitted if the connection does not hold any locks.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="locks_waiting">
        Space-separated list of the names of OVSDB locks that the connection is
        currently waiting to acquire.  Omitted if the connection is not waiting
        for any locks.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="locks_lost">
        Space-separated list of the names of OVSDB locks that the connection
        has had stolen by another OVSDB client.  Omitted if no locks have been
        stolen from this connection.
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="n_connections"
              type='{"type": "integer", "minInteger": 2}'>
        <p>
          When <ref column="target"/> specifies a connection method that
          listens for inbound connections (e.g. <code>ptcp:</code> or
          <code>pssl:</code>) and more than one connection is actually active,
          the value is the number of active connections.  Otherwise, this
          key-value pair is omitted.
        </p>
        <p>
          When multiple connections are active, status columns and key-value
          pairs (other than this one) report the status of one arbitrarily
          chosen connection.
        </p>
      </column>

      <column name="status" key="bound_port" type='{"type": "integer"}'>
          When <ref column="target"/> is <code>ptcp:</code> or
          <code>pssl:</code>, this is the TCP port on which the OVSDB server is
          listening.  (This is is particularly useful when <ref
          column="target"/> specifies a port of 0, allowing the kernel to
          choose any available port.)
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Connection Parameters">
      <p>
        Additional configuration for a connection between the manager
        and the Open Halon Database.
      </p>

      <column name="other_config" key="dscp"
                type='{"type": "integer"}'>
        The Differentiated Service Code Point (DSCP) is specified using 6 bits
        in the Type of Service (TOS) field in the IP header. DSCP provides a
        mechanism to classify the network traffic and provide Quality of
        Service (QoS) on IP networks.

        The DSCP value specified here is used when establishing the connection
        between the manager and the Open Halon.  If no value is specified, a
        default value of 48 is chosen.  Valid DSCP values must be in the range
        0 to 63.
      </column>
    </group>

    <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="external_ids"/>
      <column name="other_config"/>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="SSL">
    SSL configuration for an System.

    <column name="private_key">
      Name of a PEM file containing the private key used as the switch's
      identity for SSL connections to the controller.
    </column>

    <column name="certificate">
      Name of a PEM file containing a certificate, signed by the
      certificate authority (CA) used by the controller and manager,
      that certifies the switch's private key, identifying a trustworthy
      switch.
    </column>

    <column name="ca_cert">
      Name of a PEM file containing the CA certificate used to verify
      that the switch is connected to a trustworthy controller.
    </column>

    <column name="bootstrap_ca_cert">
      If set to <code>true</code>, then Open Halon will attempt to
      obtain the CA certificate from the controller on its first SSL
      connection and save it to the named PEM file. If it is successful,
      it will immediately drop the connection and reconnect, and from then
      on all SSL connections must be authenticated by a certificate signed
      by the CA certificate thus obtained.  <em>This option exposes the
      SSL connection to a man-in-the-middle attack obtaining the initial
      CA certificate.</em>  It may still be useful for bootstrapping.
    </column>

    <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="external_ids"/>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="CLI_Alias">
    Alias configurations for the command line interface.

    <column name="alias_name">
      Shortcut name configured by the user for a set of commands.
    </column>

    <column name="alias_definition">
      The list of commands to be executed when the shortcut is used.
      Different commands can be separated by ";". Runtime arguments can be
      specified using $1, $2 etc. Any extra arguments, will be added at the
      end of last command.
      Eg: Execute the command "alias mycmd hostname $1; console length $2;
      console width $3" to configure "mycmd" as shortcut.
      On executing "mycmd Switch1 80 24", it will be expanded to
      "hostname Switch1; console length 80; console width 24".
      "mycmd" will be stored in alias_name" and
      "hostname $1; console length $2; console width $3" will be saved in
      alias_definition.
    </column>

    <group title="Common Columns">
      The overall purpose of these columns is described under <code>Common
      Columns</code> at the beginning of this document.

      <column name="external_ids"/>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="bufmon">
    <p>
      Configuration and status of the counters per Capacity Monitoring feature
    </p>
    <group title="Counter identification">
      <column name="hw_unit_id">
        Identifies the ASIC that counter belongs to.
      </column>

      <column name="name">
        Name of the counter as it will be shown in the management systems and will
        be referenced by all the interested agents. No spaces should be used in the name.
      </column>

      <column name="counter_vendor_specific_info">
        Contains any information that might help ASIC specific driver to
        identify the counter. Both keys and values are driver and ASIC specific.
      </column>
    </group>
    <group title="Configuration">
      <column name="enabled">
        Specifies whether counter is enabled.
      </column>

      <column name="trigger_threshold">
        Specifies counter specific threshold that would trigger collection.
      </column>
    </group>
    <group title="Status">
      <column name="counter_value">
        Last collected value of the counter.
      </column>
      <column name="status">
        Specifies the status of the counter.
      </column>
    </group>
  </table>

  <table name="DHCP_Server">

    <p>
      DHCP Server configuration.
    </p>

    <group title="Configuration">
      <column name="ranges">
        Dynamic IP address ranges.
      </column>

      <column name="static_hosts">
        Static leases.
      </column>

      <column name="dhcp_options">
        DHCP options settings.
      </column>

      <column name="matches">
        Matching incoming DHCP options.
      </column>

      <column name="bootp">
        BOOTP options for the network boot of DHCP clients.
      </column>
    </group>

  </table>

  <table name="DHCPSrv_Range">

    <p>
      Dynamic IP address ranges configuration of the DHCP server.
    </p>

    <column name="name">
      Identifier for DHCP Server IP address range configuration. This has
      to be unique across all DHCP ranges and across all VRFs.
    </column>

    <column name="start_ip_address">
      Specifies the start IPv4/IPv6 address of the dynamic IP address range.
    </column>

    <column name="end_ip_address">
      Specifies the end IPv4/IPv6 address of the dynamic IP address range.
      If not specifed, then for IPv4 address family - end ip address would
      be calculated based on the configured netmask for this range or
      based on the netmask of the interface that received the DHCP request
      and for IPv6 family - end ip address would be calculated based on the
      constructor template configuration.
    </column>

    <column name="set_tag">
      Sets an alphanumeric label that marks the network so that dhcp options
      would be specified on a per-network basis.
    </column>

    <column name="match_tags">
      Specifies the list of the tags that would be matched for the
      incoming DHCP request on the interfaces whose IP addresses are
      in the configured range.
    </column>

    <column name="is_static">
      Set this value to <code>true</code> to assign static IP addresses
      to DHCP clients that have static host configuration. If the value
      is set to <code>false</code>, then the IP addresses in this range
      would be use for dynamic allocation. If not specifed, the IP address
      range would be used for dynamic allocation.
    </column>

    <column name="lease_duration">
      Specifies the lease expiry time in minutes. If not specified,
      default value of one hour (60) would be used.
    </column>

    <column name="netmask">
      This is used only in IPv4 address ranges configuration.
      Specifies the netmask that would be used for the assigned IP addresses
      in this range and this would be sent to DHCP clients. If end ip address
      is not configured for this range, then end ip address would be chosen
      based on the netmask. If netmask is not specified, then netmask of
      the switch interface that received the DHCP request would be used.
    </column>

    <column name="broadcast">
      This is used only in IPv4 address ranges configuration.
      Specifies the broadcast address that would be used for the assigned
      IP addresses in this range and this would be sent to DHCP clients.
      If not specified, broadcast address of the switch interface that
      received the DHCP request would be used.
    </column>

    <column name="constructor">
      This is used only in IPv6 address ranges configuration.
      Specifies the interface whose IP address would be used
      to calculate the end IP address for this range.
      This is used when end ip address is not specified.
    </column>

    <column name="prefix_len">
      This is used only in IPv6 address ranges configuration.
      Specifies the prefix length that would be used for the
      assigned IPv6 addresses. If not specifed, default value
      of 64 would be used.
    </column>

  </table>

  <table name="DHCPSrv_Static_Host">

    <p>
      Static leases configured by the user.
    </p>

    <column name="ip_address">
      Specifies the static IP address that should be assigned to
      the specific host.This ip address may contain an IPv4
      address or an IPv6 address, or both.
    </column>

    <column name="mac_addresses">
      Specifies the list of MAC addresses of the DHCP hosts to which the
      static IP address would be assigned. If more than one MAC addresses
      are specified, it would work reliably only if one MAC address
      is active at a time.
    </column>

    <column name="set_tags">
      Specifies the list of tags associated with the DHCP request.
      When a DHCP request from the specific DHCP client is received,
      the list of configured tags would be set
      and used to selectively send DHCP options for the client.
    </column>

    <column name="client_hostname">
      Specifies the client hostname of the DHCP client to which the configured
      static IP address would be assigned.
    </column>

    <column name="client_id">
      Specifies the client id of the DHCP client to which the configured
      static IP address would be assigned,
    </column>

    <column name="lease_duration">
      Specifies the lease expiry time in minutes. If not specified,
      default value of one hour (60) would be used.
    </column>

  </table>

  <table name="DHCPSrv_Option">

    <p>
      Configuration to specify extra options (other than standard options) that
      would be sent to the DHCP clients.
    </p>

    <column name="match_tags">
      The option and option value specified in the configuration would be
      sent only if the DHCP request from the client matches all the tags
      specified in this list.
    </column>

    <column name="option_name">
      Specifies the name of the extra option that should be sent to the
      DHCP clients.
    </column>

    <column name="option_number">
      Specifies the number of the extra option that should be sent to the
      DHCP clients. The option number would be ignored if option name
      is specified.
    </column>

    <column name="option_value">
      Specifies the value of the extra option that should be sent to the
      DHCP clients.
    </column>

    <column name="ipv6">
      Set this value to <code>true</code> if the configured option is for IPv6
      and set to <code>false</code> for IPv4 option. If not specifed,
      the configured option would be used for IPv4.
    </column>

  </table>

  <table name="DHCPSrv_Match">

    <p>
      Configuration to set tags for the incoming DHCP requests based on
      the options and its value sent by the clients.
    </p>

    <column name="set_tag">
      Specifies the name of the tag that would be set if the incoming
      DHCP request has the configured option and the value.
    </column>

    <column name="option_name">
      Specifies the name of the option that should be sent by the client
      to set the configured tag for DHCP requests.
    </column>

    <column name="option_number">
      Specifies the number of the extra option that should be sent by the
      client to set the configured tag for DHCP requests. The option number
      would be ignored if option name is specified.
    </column>

    <column name="option_value">
      Specifies the value of the option that should be sent
      by the client to set the configured tag for DHCP requests.
      If the value is not specified, then the tag
      would be set for any value of the option.
    </column>

  </table>

</database>
